走起来
Move!
我天生就是打仗的料
- I was born for battle.
具备打仗应有的素质
Built for it.
有时在战斗中 精心设计的计划会遭破坏
Sometimes in battle, a perfectly crafted plan gets compromised.
一位真正的将军 当场就能想出一个更好的计划
A true general comes up with a better one right there on the spot,
冒着风险采取行动
working without a net
然后在雷鸣般的掌声中 圆满地完成任务
and sticking the landing to thunderous applause.
快点 狗崽子们
- Hurry up, you dogs!
快走
Let's go! Let's go!
他们在哪儿
- Where are they?
他们当时直冲我们过来 然后转到了一条侧轨上
- They were coming straight at us and then veered away on a sidetrack.
这条轨道拐向西南方
This line bends Southwest.
以那个速度 他们此刻可能已在20公里之外
At that speed, they could be 20 kilometers away by now.
或者已调头 跟在我们后面
- Or coming about to nip at our heels.
对不起 先生 这事事先没一点征兆
- I'm sorry, sir. There was no warning.
当然 他们确保了这一点 不是吗  趁没有卫星信号
- No, they saw to that, didn't they? No satellite coverage.
在无月之夜 从阴影中伏击我们
A moonless night. An ambush from the shadows!
就跟他们离开的那天一样懦弱
- As cowardly as the day they left, sir.
不 他们从我们身边经过肯定有阴谋
- No, they didn't drive by for nothing.
把前灯开到最大
Forward lamps to full.
刹车
Brake!
在战斗中 有那么一刻 你被对方的第一击击中后
There's a moment in a fight when that first blow lands
一切仿佛都静止了
and everything stops.
在那一瞬间 你心开目明 认清了自己是谁
And in that flash of clarity, you know who you are.
我会竭尽全力夺回我的机车
I'll push as hard as it takes to get my engine back.
1023节车厢长的雪国列车
Snowpiercer, 1,023 cars long.
加大马力 冲过去
Full thrust. Push through it.
-可是 先生 如果车轴… -全速前进 工程师 快
- Sir, if that axel-- - Full power, Engineer. Now!
干得漂亮 先生 第一局您赢了
- Well done, sir. Round one to you.
不 他们放那个陷阱 不是为了让我们停下
- No, no, that trap wasn't meant to stop us.
而是为了让我们减速
It was meant to slow us down.
凯文 我们今天不能受任何挫折
We can't have any setbacks today, Kevin.
鲁丝的人会受到激励的 去把他们找出来
Ruth's people will be energized. Find them.
我正好知道该从何着手
- I know just where to start.
手段狠点
- Take the gloves off.
杀鸡儆猴
Make an example.
就等着您这么吩咐呢
- I thought you'd never ask.
-凯文 还有件事 -您说 先生
- And Kevin? - Yes, sir.
让扎拉到这里来
- Send Zarah to me.
我们现在的速度是多少
What's our speed?
每小时14公里
- 14 kilometers an hour.
好啊 雷顿先生 你已迫使我们慢如爬行
- All right, Mr. Layton, you got us at a crawl.
你有什么花招呢
What's the play?
雷顿知道车尾对接是行不通的
Layton knows better than to connect end to end.
我手下的军靴可以直接冲进去击败他
My Jackboots would just sweep in and crush him.
所以 他会从侧面袭击我们
So he's going to peck at us from the side.
他需要一条并行的轨道
- He needs parallel track.
而这片铁路站场就像个迷宫 布满了并行轨道
- And this rail yard is an entire maze of it.
他们摆脱了陷阱 但速度慢了下来
He broke free of the snare but slowed down.
我们可以在这些侧线上 赶上他们 与其并行
- We can get right up alongside him in these sidings.
他们距离那里还有2公里
They'll be in position in 2 kilometers.
本 调头
- Bring us around, Ben.
-收到 -有多少时间
- Copy that. - How long we got?
三四分钟
- Three, four minutes.
好 机警点 咱们把这事给办了
- All right, stay sharp. Let's get this done.
我去确保乔西已做好准备
I'll make sure Josie's ready.
贝丝
- Bess.
贝丝提尔
♪ Bess Till
-贝丝  -奥德丽 闭嘴
♪ Bess! - Audrey, shut it.
出什么事了 是他吗
- What's happening? Is it him?
他的脑袋被插在长矛上时 你就会知道是他了
- You'll know it's him when his head is on a pike.
你准备好了吗
- You ready for this?
本开到他们边上后 我就跳过去 进大爱丽丝的机车
- Ben takes us close. I jump over, breach the Big Alice engine,
然后你们重新连接两车
and you reconnect.
我们只有一次机会
- We only get one shot at it.
那就最好别错失这个机会
- Well, then, better not miss it.
扎拉
- Zarah,
你来得正是时候
just in time.
我觉得你该看看这个
Thought you should be here for this.
以人质的身份还是旁观者的身份
- As a hostage or a spectator?
以我的红颜知己的身份
- As my confidante, nothing less.
来
Come.
来啊
Come on.
看一下
Have a look.
看到没
See,
从我们侧翼悄悄追上来的 是你的旧相好
that's your old life creeping up our flank.
他们要攻击我们吗
- Are they attacking?
也许他们是来投降的
- Maybe they're here to surrender.
你看到白旗了吗
You see any white flags?
-没有 -没有
- No. - No.
如果非得让我猜的话
No, and if I had to guess,
我觉得他们是冲着龙首而来的
I'd say they're trying to cut the head off the snake.
但我有个惊喜要送给他们
But I have a surprise for them.
（W 压缩氧）
传下去
- Heave.
快点传
Heave.
不管这些锡罐是做什么用的 肯定不是什么好事
- Well, whatever these tin cans are for can't be good.
派克 你有什么计划
- Pike, man, what's the plan?
专心干活
- Keep your eyes on your work.
-继续传 -嘿 别呆站着
- Heave. - And quit standing around! Let's go.
快点 你在干什么呢
- Come on. What are you doing?
好 该行动了 我去引开他们 你们去找鲁丝
- All right, time to move. I'll distract them. You guys get to Ruth.
不行 不能这么做
- No. Whoa, whoa. That's not how it works, man.
你现在是负责人了 你不能被抓
You're in charge now. You don't get caught.
接着
Catch.
我们已经就位
- We're in position.
（冷封门已锁）
（冷封门解锁）
乔西 是时候了
- Josie, it's time.
在外面当心点
Be careful out there.
我会毁掉那引擎的 别担心
- I'll breach the bastard, don't worry.
就是现在 鱼叉炮
Now! Harpoon!
准备发射
- Deploy.
正在打开冷封门
- Opening cold-lock.
威尔福德有一个 像大炮的玩意儿 往后撤
Wilford has a cannon or something. Pull back!
马上更换轨道 乔西 抓紧了
- Switch track. Josie, hold on.
（轨道切换）
-我们要脱轨了 -设法稳住
- We're derailing! - Try to stabilize.
干得漂亮
- Well done.
你总能令我惊讶
Never fails to amaze me.
受到这么大刺激 却没什么反应
You take so much in and give so little back.
我刚射残了你男人的列车 扎拉 可你连眼睛都没眨一下
I just hobbled your man, Zarah, and you didn't even flinch.
照这个速度下去 黎明前这场战争就会结束
At this rate, the war will be over by daybreak.
拜托 嘿 这节车厢受损 我们得离开这里
- Come on. The car is damaged. We gotta go. Let's go.
得把车厢断开 否则我们会脱轨的
- We have to cut it loose. It's gonna derail us.
从这里断开 那可是四节车厢啊
- Cut here? That's four cars.
这是最近的连接处 这是唯一的选择
- It's the closest J-link. It's the only option.
-阿莎在那后面 -我们没时间了
- Asha's back there. - We don't have time.
快走
- Go.
你没事吧
- You okay?
谢谢
Thank you.
她在外头坚持了八年 不能上我们列车第二天就被害死呀
- She waited eight years outside. Can't very well kill her on day two.
安全栓已解除
- Safety's off.
开始断开连接
- Disconnecting now
（连接处解锁）
断开了
And we're clear.
这边走
- Here.
你在这里会更安全
You'll be safer up here.
嘿
Hey...
你不会有事吧
You gonna be okay?
把灯关了
- Turn out the lights.
没问题
- Sure.
待着别动 好吗
Hold fast, okay?
我们有麻烦了
- We have a problem.
威尔福德不见了
Wilford's gone.
他关闭了列车的信号和灯光 不知道他们在哪里
His train went dark. He could be anywhere now.
关闭全车上下的通讯和信号传输 停止一切声响
- Switch off comms and transmitters tip to tail. Not a peep.
扎拉 你怎么还站着呀
Zarah, what are you doing still on your feet?
你一定累坏了 过来
You must be exhausted. Come.
那你有什么打算
- So what are you planning?
稍微歇一下对我们有好处
Bit of a lull. It'll do us good.
喘口气
Catch our breath.
我在你和这孩子身上投入了很多
I've invested a lot in you. And the child.
我只是想让你待在我身边
I just want to keep you near me,
为了保护你
for your protection.
而且如果我在机车里 他们就不会攻击这里
- And because they won't attack the engine if I'm in it.
没错
- Right.
十几公里长的列车 你怎么能跟丢了呢
- How do you lose a 10-mile train?
是我们把他带到这片迷宫里的
- We were the ones that led him into this maze.
他可能想逃出去 这六条线路通向谷外
- He could be running. These six routes head out of the valley.
如果他进入了直线轨道 我们就失去了优势
If he gets to linear track, we'll lose our advantage.
嗯 他也可能 正在下一个拐角等着我们
- Yeah, or he's around the next corner, laying in wait.
他会把我们的列车一节节地废掉
- He's gonna pick us off piece by piece.
当时那玩意的炮口正对着我
I looked into the muzzle of that thing.
我们必须找到他 我们能去高一点的地方吗
- We need to get eyes on him. Can we get to higher ground?
这里 这条轨道沿着山脊线 应该能让我们看到整个盆地
- Here, track follows the ridgeline. Should give us a view of the whole basin.
好 就这么办 把灯熄了 如果他打算隐身 我们也一样
- Okay, let's do it. Lights out. If he's gonna go dark, so do we.
小情侣 起来干活了
- Up and at 'em, lovebirds.
凯文 出去 你太过分了
- Kevin! Get out. How dare you?
夜车被我征用了
- Commandeering the Nightcar.
凯文
- Ugh, Kevin.
谁批准的
- On whose authority?
你可以称之为“战时举措”
- Call it a wartime measure.
你们没听说吗 雷顿回来了
Oh, you didn't hear? Layton's back.
起来
Up.
还有活儿要干呢
There's work to do.
要不你去煮点咖啡吧
- Why don't you, um, go put some coffee on?
谁在那里
- Who--who's there?
我是来见囚犯的 我是她的律师
- Here to see the prisoner. I'm her lawyer.
我觉得现在已经没有律师这回事了
- I don't think that's a thing anymore.
军靴 你把头盔摘掉了
- Lose your helmet, Jackboot?
嘿 别这样 哥们
- Hey, come on, man.
嘿
Hey.
你认识我吗
- Do you know me?
你是个末等人 抱歉 我不知道你叫什么
- You're--you're a Tailie. Forgive me, I-I don't know your name.
我认识你
- I know you.
你姓惠金斯
Whiggins.
对
- Yes.
关于末等人 有两件事你该知道
- Well, there's two things you should know about Tailies.
我们的记性很好 而且打仗我们总赢
We have long memories and we win wars.
是吗
- Oh, yeah?
上一场战争是我们赢了 这一场也一样
We won the last one. And we'll win this one.
你想当个碍我们事的人吗
And do you wanna be the guy who stands in the way?
惠金斯
Hmm, Whiggins?
律师先生 给你十分钟的时间
- You have ten minutes, Counselor.
我替你开门
Let me just get the door for you.
派克
- Pike?
姑娘 你的气色不错啊 没有缺胳膊少腿
- You're looking good, girl, with those arms dangling down.
你不该来这里 太危险了
- You shouldn't be here. It's too dangerous.
-我得把你弄出去 -等等 告诉我发生了什么
- I'm gonna get you out of here. - Wait, wait, wait. Tell me what happened.
威尔福德用大炮把雷顿赶走了 此刻我们正在黑暗中瞎转
- Wilford drove Layton off with cannon fire. Now we're rolling around in the dark.
如果威尔福德在躲着雷顿 那我们就得给雷顿发信号
- Well, if Wilford is hiding, then we need to signal Layton.
我得先把你救出去
- I'm gonna get you out of here first.
不行的 要救我 你得先杀了惠金斯 然后找到克利福德
- You can't. You'd have to kill Whiggins, and then you'd have to find Clifford
把他也杀了 因为钥匙在他手里
and kill him too, 'cause he's got the keys.
还有谁 继续说
- Go on.
派克先生
- Pike, Mr. Pike,
你是个好人 一个勇敢的好人
you're a dear man and a brave one,
但这场战争比你我都重要
but this war is bigger than us.
我要怎么给雷顿发信号呢
- How do I signal Layton?
我有个主意
- I've got an idea,
但你得去列车前列的待客部
but you'll have to get uptrain to hospitality.
阿莎 你还好吗 在这里还行吗
Asha. Hey, you good in there?
对不起 我们让你卷进了 最激烈的对抗中 来
I'm sorry, I dropped you right in the thick of it. Here.
嘿
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
发生什么事了
- What's going on?
威尔福德先生把这列车弄坏了
Did Mr. Wilford cripple the train?
没有 听着 这只是猫鼠之争 好吗 没事的
- No, look, it's just some cat and mouse, all right?
你们是猫
It's fine.
你们八个人 要对付伟大的威尔福德先生
- And you're supposed to be the cat? Eight of you against the great Mr. Wilford.
“伟大的威尔福德先生” 跟你想象中的不一样
- The great Mr. Wilford is not who you think he is.
不是他救了你们大家吗
- Isn't he the one that saved all of you?
是我们自己救了自己
- We saved our own damn selves.
他打造这列列车 只是为了自己能称王
He built all of this just so he could be king.
-那现在轮到你称王了 -不 这是我们的私人恩怨 好吗
- So now it's your turn? - No. This is personal for us, okay?
登上列车时 我有一个伴侣 她现在怀着身孕
I have a partner that I boarded with. I have a child on the way.
如果你这么做是为了一个孩子 你会做出让自己后悔的事的
- Oh, if you're doing this for a child, you will do things that you will regret.
我只是过来警告你
- I just came in to warn you.
我们不会放弃的
We are not giving up.
局势好转之前 会变得更加恶劣 明白吗
This is gonna get worse before it gets better, okay?
-明白 -坚持住
- Okay. - Hold on.
你是我的阳光
- ♪ You are my sunshine
我唯一的阳光
♪ My only sunshine
当天空灰暗时
♪ You make me happy
会带给我欢乐
♪ When skies are gray
你永远都不知
♪ You'll never know, dear
我有多么爱你
♪ How much I love you
请别将我的阳光带走
♪ Please don't take My sunshine away
要知道 你唱歌的时候
- You know, when you sing,
我几乎都能说服自己说 你的为人并不坏
I can almost convince myself you're not a horrible person.
谢谢
- Thank you.
然后我会想起来你只翻唱别人的歌 所以歌词其实不代表你的心声
- And then I remember you only sing covers, so the words aren't actually yours.
歌词只是点缀而已
- Lyrics are just dressing.
我只为他歌唱
I sing for him.
老天
- Oh, God.
你显得很不屑
- You scoff,
但归根结底 那就是全部
but at the end of the day, that's all there is.
你为之歌唱的那个人
A person you sing for.
贝丝 你的那个人是谁
Who's that to you, Bess?
你一路坚持到了世界末日 居然会没有一个那样的人
How do you get all the way to the end of the world and have no one?
我有
- I have people.
谁
- Who?
雷顿、扎拉、罗齐
- Layton, Zarah, Roche.
罗齐
- Roche?
没错 罗齐
- Yeah, Roche.
他就像我的导师兼益友
He was like a mentor to me and--and a friend.
尽管我跟他对着干 他还是罩着我
Even though I fought him, he-- he had my back.
不 我不会为他歌唱
No, I don't-- I don't sing for him.
但是每一天
But not a day goes
我都在想着把他从抽屉房弄出来
by when I don't think about getting him out of those Drawers.
我很遗憾
- I'm sorry.
希望他能活下来
I hope he survived.
是呀
- Yeah.
我们在山脊上了 注意观察
- We're at the ridge. Eyes up.
如果他在山谷里 这是能找到他的最佳位置
If he is in the valley, this is the best vantage point.
-有发现吗  -提尔
- Anything? - Till?
没有 什么都没发现
Negative. There's nothing.
但他们不可能就这样消失不见啊
- But they can't just vanish.
（待客部）
（W 新年流程）
好戏登场
- Time to put on a show.
看南面 在山谷的尽头 你们看到了吗
To the south, far end of the valley. Are you guys seeing this?
我的天啊 等等
- Oh, my God. Wait, wait, wait.
那是…
Is that-
我们的支持者还在
They're still with us.
看到你了 约瑟夫
- We see you, Joseph.
他正试图逃跑 在山脊东侧 往干线方向去
- He's making a break for it. East over the ridge to the trunk line.
他想偷偷溜出铁路站场 我们在这里有战术优势
He wants to sneak out of the rail yard because it's where we have tactical advantage.
他要是跑出去了 接下去好几天就都是直线轨道
- If he gets out of the valley, he's looking at days of linear track.
我们能赶到他前面去吗
- Can we beat him to it?
-艾莉  -不行
- Alex? - No.
我不知道 也许行吧 我没把握
I don't know, maybe. It's all assumptions.
那我们还等什么 加速啊
- What are we waiting for? Pedal down.
我们在山口截住他
- Let's cut 'em off at the pass.
工程师 加足马力
- Full throttle, Engineer.
先生 恕我直言 我们的油耗非常快
- Sir, with respect, we're draining really fast.
稍微开慢点 燃油效率会更高
A few ticks slower would be more efficient.
他们已经看到我们了 他们要来了
- They've seen us. They're coming!
用上所有的储备燃油 越过这该死的山脊
Tap every last reserve and get us over that bloody ridge!
拜托 你这是干什么
- Come on! What are you doing?
强壮男孩 给你挑
- So you have a choice, Strong Boy.
接下来要我砸碎两根手指呢 还是砸碎你的拇指
I can take two fingers next time or I can take your thumb.
你也可以聪明一点
Or you could be smart
就像你自告奋勇 到我桌子这里来时一样
like when you bravely volunteered to step up to my table here.
威尔福德只是要你提供信息 报出你同党的姓名
Wilford just needs you to start talking and name your collaborators.
不干
No.
-不干  -拜托 别再折磨他了
- No? - Come on. Leave him alone!
-抓住他 -不要
- Hold him. - Ah, no! No!
够了
Stop!
我没答应过要趟这浑水
- I didn't sign up for this.
我只是想经营夜总会 提供酒水和歌曲
Just wanted to serve some drinks and play some tunes.
你能放松点吗 战争都是丑陋的
- Would you relax? War is not pretty.
但威尔福德会奖励我们的
But Wilford will reward us.
前提是他能赢
- If he wins.
他当然会赢
- Of course he'll win.
万一他输了呢
If he doesn't?
到时候雷顿进来发现这件事 知道我们也在场 怎么办
- And Layton rolls in here, finds this? Finds us?
威尔福德的傀儡夫妻
Wilford's little wedding puppets.
行刑的人又不是我们 我们只是提供了场地而已
- We're not the torturers, all right? We're just providing a venue.
我觉得被肢解的这个家伙 可不会这么认为
- I'm sure the mutilated guy will be quick to sort that out.
听着 如果你不打算开口
Look, if you're not gonna talk,
那你就不再需要这舌头了
I guess you don't need that tongue anymore.
请抓好他
Hold him, please.
抓好他
Hold him, hold him.
张嘴
Open up.
听着 即便我们追上了他 我们还是要应付他的鱼叉炮
- Look, even if we catch up with him, we still have the harpoon issue,
我们也没法进行车尾对接
and we can't connect end to end.
因为我们绝对打不过他的军靴
We'll never overpower his Jackboots.
没错
- No.
所以我们得想办法进入机车 我们需要引开他的注意力
So we need a plan to get into his engine. We need a distraction.
奥德丽
- Audrey.
这是要干什么
- What's this?
手放在背后
- Hands behind your back.
手铐 我就知道你有性怪癖
- Ooh, handcuffs. I knew you had a kink.
快走
- Move.
祝好运
- Good luck.
这里的气氛很压抑嘛
- It's moody in here.
坐下
- Sit.
还有多远
- How much further?
快到山脊了 但我们的燃油即将耗尽
- We're almost at the ridge, but we're basically running on fumes.
继续开 它能行的 然后就胜券在握了
- Keep pushing. She'll make it. Then we're home free.
悠着点 本
- Nice and easy, Ben.
约瑟夫
- Joseph.
大爱丽丝 这里是雪国列车 请回话
- Big Alice, this is Snowpiercer. Come in.
雪国列车呼叫大爱丽丝 请回话
Snowpiercer to Big Alice, come in.
先生 我该回答吗
- Sir, should--should I answer?
不要
- No, no.
大爱丽丝 请回答
- Come in, Big Alice.
这里是大爱丽丝 我在跟谁通话呢
- This is Big Alice. To whom am I speaking?
威尔福德 我是那个 挡在你和开放轨道之间的人
- I'm the guy standing between you and open track, Wilford.
我看到了 这么说 现在就看谁的胆子更大了 是吗
- I see that. So it's a game of chicken, is it?
按你们行进的速度 我觉得你开不到那么远
- At the rate you're going, I don't think you'll make it this far.
大爱丽丝的韧劲比你想象的强
- Oh, Big Alice has more fight than you know.
雷顿 这次会面是你发起的
You called this meeting, Layton.
所以 有话快说 没必要在这里做无聊的争执
So go on, or are we just gonna stand here pissing off our prows?
我们离开时 你我有个约定
- When we left, we made a deal.
我确保奥德丽安全…
I keep Audrey safe--
我记得 我就不把大家杀了
- I remember, and I don't murder everyone.
是的 我记得我们的约定
Yes, I remember the deal.
我要提醒你一句 那是在胁迫下作出的约定
It was made under duress, I'll remind you.
但我还是遵守了
But I stuck to it.
扎拉呢
- Where's Zarah?
她就在这里
- She's right here.
满面红光
Positively glowing.
我在这里 安德烈 我没事
- I'm here, Andre. I'm okay.
奥德丽呢
- And Audrey?
我想听到她的声音
I want to hear her.
我得知道她没事
I need to know she's all right.
交出列车控制权 你就可以亲自跟她说话了
- Surrender the train and you can tell her yourself.
交出控制权
- Surrender?
我们会给你们一节头等车厢 提供美食酒水
- We'll give you a car in First, food, drink.
你们俩可以相守到老
You two can live out your years together.
也就是说 我把一切都给你
- So I--I give you absolutely everything,
而你只会给我一点小小的恩赐
and you give me a little piece back in return?
这个提议太可笑了吧 雷顿
That's quite some offer, Layton.
我的提议是 用非暴力的形式了结这件事
- The offer is, we end this without violence,
否则就回到那个铁路站场 我们会把你拆成碎片
or you could roll back down into that rail yard and we'll pick you apart.
完了 先生 燃油耗尽了
- That's it, sir. We're tapped.
我拒绝
- No deal.
我想听听她的声音
I...I want to hear her voice.
约瑟夫
- Joseph.
（危险）
好了 本 我到冷封门了
- All right, Ben, I'm at the cold-Lock.
快了
Soon, soon.
设置自动驾驶 急速后退
- Auto-engaging hot reverse.
我们应该调换一下车尾车头 让大爱丽丝在后面推
We should switch helms and get Big Alice pushing again.
停车 工程师
- Full stop, Engineer.
关闭电源
Let her power down.
-什么  -约瑟夫
- What? - Joseph.
这不可能是好事
- That can't be good,
会是好事吗
can it?
不会
- No.
雪国列车
- Snowpiercer,
我们没动力 启动不了了
we are dead on the tracks.
如果你们不跟我们连接 列车上所有的人都会冻死
If you don't reconnect, everyone will freeze to death.
你这是不顾一切了
- You're desperate.
而你则没得选择
- And you have no choice.
准备连接 哈维…
- Prepare to connect. Javi, abre una cerveza, amigo.
指挥官 把你的突击小组 派到连接点去
- Commander, move your boarding party to the connection point.
发电不足容量
- Generation deficit.
整个列车的温度正在下降
Train-wide temperature is dropping right now.
最好把你的毛衣穿上
- Better get your woolies on.
来吧 小伙子们 准备好了吗
- All right, boys, you ready?
出去 瞄准中心点 记住射击目标
- Move out. Remember where to aim.
他们在准备连接了
- They're preparing to dock.
他们别无选择
- They've got no choice.
又要开始了 快走 快
Let's go, let's go. Move, move, move.
驾驶舱没问题
- Cap okay?
嘿 留神点 进去
- Hey, watch your back. Move it, move it!
这太疯狂了 本
- This is crazy, Ben.
是呀 强盗生涯就是如此
- Yeah, pirate's life.
见鬼
- Shit.
没事的
- You're all right.
用你敢开的最快速度倒车
Just reverse her in as fast as you dare.
见鬼
- Shit.
我们就位之前不要与对方连接
- And don't reconnect until we're in position.
好了 各位 记住 我们要先把对方清除干净
- Hey, remember, people, we're gonna clear it first.
武器准备好 上
- Weapons ready? Move!
老天
- Christ.
乔瑟芬
Josephine.
她回来了
She's back.
真够有种的
The bloody balls.
你是爬上来的吗 小流浪汉
Did you climb aboard, you little hobo?
这里有孕妇哦
Uh-uh, baby on board.
不 你不会的
No, you won't.
她不会的
She won't.
见鬼 真够狠的
Damn. Good one.
叫你的人退下 否则我就把你扔出列车去
- Tell your men to stand down or I will throw you off this train.
我是首席工程师威尔福德
- This is Head Engineer Wilford.
突击小组 退下
Boarding party, stand down.
我们不打算…
We will not be taking...
用武力拿下雪国列车
Snowpiercer by force.
退下 放下武器
Stand down. Weapons down.
我的天啊
- Oh, my God.
这下开心了
- Happy now?
快说
- Say it!
安德烈雷顿拥有了列车控制权
- Andre Layton has the train.
雪国列车的公民们…
- Citizens of Snowpiercer...
我们回来了
We're back.
50米 40米
50 meters, 40 meters,
25米
25 meters...
不可能就这样结束了
- It can't be just over.
我觉得该是选择胜利一方的时候了
- Well, I think it's about time we get on the right side of history.
给
- Here you go.
奥斯
Oz,
我非常爱你
I love you so much.
抵抗军万岁
- Long live the Resistance!
-找到了 -鲁丝
- Ah, found it. - Ruth?
安德烈
- Andre.
你没穿制服 我都认不出你了
- I never would have found you. You're in civvies.
我记得威尔福德 把他的好酒藏在这里了
I remembered that Wilford had a secret tipple up here.
-我正需要喝两口 没错 -我想着我们可以庆祝一下
- Oh, could use some of that. - Wanna celebrate? - Yes.
欢迎回来 你能回来真是太好了
- Oh, welcome home. It's good to have you back.
我就知道你能把大家团结在一起
- I knew you'd hold everyone together.
干得漂亮
Well done.
我们来喝吧
- Let's do it.
把他们放出来
- Take them out.
他情况稳定
- He's stable.
卡莉情况稳定…还有安娜…
Carly's stable. And Anne--
哈维
- Javi.
嘿
Hey.
天啊
- Oh, man.
非洲之角这个暖点 你真的相信它能维持生命生长
- This warm spot, the Horn of Africa, you really believe it can support life?
是的 鲁丝 我们的未来就在那里 我非常坚信这一点
- Yeah, our future is there, Ruth. I believe it with all my heart.
通往非洲之角的轨道是整个铁路网内
- You know, the Horn of Africa, the approach is maybe the worst stretch of track on
最糟的一段
the entire network.
而且气候崩溃时 那里发生过一场战争
And there was a war there when the climate crashed.
嗯 我记得
- Yeah, yeah, I remember.
大家都累坏了 安德烈
- The people are tired, Andre.
这六个月艰苦漫长 而你回来后的第一个命令
It's been a long six months, and your first order
就是要让他们再经历更多艰辛
is gonna be to steer them right back into more hardship?
我不会下达命令 我们会投票决定
- Mm-mmm, there won't be an order. We'll put it to a vote.
-投票  -是的
- A vote? - Yeah.
我们要让大家看看 民主已经获胜 我们要一起选择前进的道路
We'll show them that democracy has won. We'll choose our path forward together.
你已经准备好面对投票结果了
- And you're prepared for the outcome of this vote?
我会让大家相信这值得冒险一试
- I am going to convince them that it is worth the risk.
雪国列车已经损毁不堪 不抛锚已是万幸
Snowpiercer's running on duct tape and prayers.
这是一个真实的能下车的机会
This is a real opportunity to get off.
这也是对你的投票 安德烈
- It's also a vote on you, Andre.
列车上的很多人并不支持你的领导
Much of the train doesn't support your leadership.
这件事不止关系到我
- This isn't just about me.
这也是梅兰妮会想要的
It's what Melanie would have wanted.
那好
- All right.
我去通知公证处
I'll, uh, inform the notary.
我知道列车上的所有人 都会慎重地投出这一票
I know that everyone aboard will take their vote to heart,
但万一投票结果是“不去” 你有这思想准备吗
but are you prepared to accept it if they vote no?
你最好仔细琢磨一下要怎么说服大家
You better think long and hard about exactly what it is you're gonna tell them.
只准你待在三等车厢 而且禁止进夜车
- You're confined to Third and barred from the Nightcar.
-约瑟夫呢  -奥德丽 你站错队伍了
- Where's Joseph? - You picked the wrong side, Audrey.
这该死的列车上有过正确的队伍吗
- Has there ever been a right side on this goddamn train?
这一切都会崩塌的 等着瞧吧
It's all gonna go to shit. You'll see.
直接扎穿了我的手
- It went straight through my hand.
这样你就能记住我们了
- Something to remember us by.
看看你呀
- Look at you.
怪物来找它的创造者
A monster come for its creator.
很有诗意吧
It's poetic, isn't it?
雷顿没法把列车团结起来的
- Layton can't hold it together, you know.
他们会再次拒绝他的领导
They'll reject him again.
我是这列车的灵魂
I am the train.
投票
- A vote?
没错
- That's right.
你今天也会有投票的权利
You'll get a vote today too.
政治
Politics.
当你是世上最后一个人的时候 就会忘记政治的存在
You forget about them when you're the last person on Earth.
谢谢你
Thank you.
先别忙着谢我
- Don't thank me just yet.
我有件事要你帮忙
There's something I need to ask of you.
安德烈 你救了我的命
- You brought me back to life, Andre.
要我帮什么
What is it?
各位乘客同伴们
- My fellow passengers...
今天是这列列车启程以来第一次
Today, for the first time since our departure...
由你们来决定我们的目的地
you will have a say in our destination,
而且你们的选择将决定我们的未来
and your choice will determine our future.
你们已经知道 梅兰妮牺牲了自己 为我们绘制了一份地图
By now, you know that Melanie's sacrifice gave us a map.
证明地球上有些地方正在变暖
Proof that there are places on the Earth that are warming.
我们之前轻装出发 快速地测试了每一个暖点
Traveling fast and light, we tested each of them.
苏拉威西岛、古吉拉特邦、马那瓜
Sulawesi, Gujarat, Managua,
阿塔卡马
the Atacama.
但它们都不合格
And each one of these let us down.
我知道 当初我们分开列车的决定
I know that you have suffered badly
害你们历尽了艰苦
because of our decision to break the train.
但还有一个地方 我觉得大家应该寄予希望
But there is one more location on which I ask you to stake your hope:
那就是非洲之角
the Horn of Africa.
返回那里的行程会充满风险
The journey to return there will be fraught with risk
艰辛还将继续
and the hardships will continue,
但这里有一个人 能让我们重树信心
but we have someone here who can renew our faith.
一个我们以前觉得不可能存在的人
Someone we had given up on believing in.
他这是在干什么
- What's he doing?
我会让她自己跟你们说
- But I'll let her tell you.
他在编瞎话
- He's bullshitting.
我叫阿莎
- My name is Asha.
我是一个幸存者
I am a survivor.
雷顿在外面找到了我
Layton found me out there, outside.
在户外 生长了树木
Along with trees,
青草
green grass...
和生命的地方
and life.
我来自新伊甸园
I come from New Eden.
我不是要你们 在我和威尔福德之间做出选择
- I'm not asking you to choose between me and Wilford.
而是请你们在我们熟悉的列车
I am asking you to choose between the train we know
和我们不熟悉的梦想之间做出选择
and the dream we don't.
非常感谢大家作出的牺牲
Thank you all so much for your sacrifices.
这个故事需要一个英雄 所以我们就带回了一个英雄
The story needed a hero, and we brought one back.
鉴于那番表演
- Well, in the wake of that performance,
投赞同票的人胜出
the yeas have it.
几乎是2比1的比例
Almost two to one.
多说一个谎又怎样呢
- What's one more lie?
区别在于 这是我们说的最后一个谎话
- The difference is, this is the last one
我很怀疑
we will have to tell.
我开始觉得这列列车需要谎言
- Well, I doubt that. I've come to think this train demands a lie.
没错 就像虚构的机车中的天才
- Yeah, like an imaginary genius in the engine.
或是梅兰妮用完美的科学手段 来拯救我们
- Or Melanie saving us with perfect science.
或是为我们指路的幸存者
- Or a survivor to show us the way.
所以…
- So...
-我们继续前进 -同意
we press on. - Agreed.
我们还能怎样
- What else are we gonna do?
乔西
- Josie?
我们最好是对的
- Well, we better be right.
各位乘客同伴们 我们伟大的征程将继续
- Fellow passengers, our great endeavor continues.
你们已表态 根据少数服从多数原则 我们将前往新伊甸园
You have spoken, and by majority rule, we are heading for New Eden.
字幕翻译：黛拉